Well, Richard, according to
all of your test results,
you are what we in the
medical field call
healthy.
In fact, you've got kind
of a glow about you.
- Oh, really?
- Absolutely.
You know, if it were medically possible,
I might even think that
you were pregnant.
Of course, I thought my
girlfriend was pregnant,
and I was sure wrong about that.
(Laughs)
Whoops! Hey, give me that ring back!
Oh, what a mess.
What a mess that was.
So, been any big changes for you,
diet or exercise?
Well, I actually got fired
as CEO of my company.
I'm working now as the CTO
under the new CEO, Jack Barker.
Wait a minute. You got a
boss at your own company?
Yeah, I know that sounds bad,
but honestly, he handles
all the budgeting,
all the VC funding.
He just negotiated a great new lease
on our new offices.
I don't know. I think this
could be great for me.
Boy, I don't think I could
have another doctor
coming in here, being my boss.
No. It'd be like, "Hey, boss,
"is it okay if I listen to his heart?
"Can I do that? Oh, no? Sorry.
"No, I won't. Okay.
- (laughing) Whatever you say!"
- (chuckles)
- Ah, funny.
- It is funny. Yeah.
But listen, if it works
for you, that's great.
Just one more thing.
I've gotta check your testicles.
Oh my God. Okay.
What, for like a hernia or something?
No. I just wanna make
sure they're still there.
(laughs)
(theme music playing)
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
♪ ♪
Oh, wow. This is going to be our office?
All of this?
Yeah, Jack said we have the whole floor.
Dinesh: Wow, look at that kitchen.
This is great.
Richard, is that our new logo?
I like it. It's clean and elegant,
but not without some danger.
Jack: Gentlemen, welcome.
I moved away from the flute-playing guy.
I don't know if you guys realized
it, but that was a little phallic.
I didn't want to waste your time with
it, so I just pulled the trigger.
Mari Sheibley did this.
Oh. Mari Sheibley.
That must've set you back a bit.
No. She's a friend.
Yeah. I know her... as well.
Casually.
So, why don't I show you
guys your new home?
Hopefully, it lives
up to your standards.
Gilfoyle: Yeah, compared to
the shit shack we're used to,
anything's an improvement.
Ah, an insult born of respect.
I'll worry when we start
complimenting each other.
Fucking dick.
I assume you saw Hiroki
putting in the water feature.
Good feng shui. Gotta have that.
This is the engineering area.
Dinesh: We're gonna work here?
That is a separate,
professionally-catered
micro-kitchen back there.
I want you hungry here, never here.
This is all great, but can
we really afford all this?
Hey, step into my office, Richard.
- Here.
- Okay.
I wanna show you something.
Dinesh: This is way better
than Erlich's shithole.
Richard: "The Conjoined
Triangles of Success"?
I invented that,
and now it's taught at business schools.
You see what's on the bottom here?
The foundation of the whole thing.
- Growth?
- Growth.
The more brilliant people
we can get working here,
then the faster we can get whatever
is in your head out into the world.
Let me tell you a story.
In 1999,
Google was a little
startup, just like we are.
And when they started bringing
in chefs and masseuses,
we thought, "They're nuts!"
But they were attracting
the best possible people,
and they were able to
create the best product,
and now they're worth over $400 billion.
And do you know the
name of that company?
Google, right? You said it at
the beginning of the story.
You're right. I did that wrong.
And the whole point is
that all of this is a sound investment
as long as we are able
to get the best people
and make the best possible product.
♪ ♪
All right. Winner gets the big monitor.
I understand how this works.
Both: Ready?
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot.
Suck it.
I should've known you'd throw rock.
That's all you know in Pakistan.
It's in your blood.
Don't you guys call it
"Rock, Rock, Rock"?
That's funny. You should type
up all your racist jokes
- on your tiny monitor.
- Is that monitor not big enough?
You need a bigger monitor?
You just put it on the list over there,
and our purchasing guy will hook you up.
- Seriously?
- Absolutely.
Hey, Jared, how about you? You
need any new gear for the office?
No, I'm BYOC.
Let me know if you need anything.
Richard, do you think it'd
be okay if I took this box?
I'm moving out of Noah's
guest house after work.
And you want to sleep in that box?
(laughs) No.
I haven't slept in a box in years. Stop.
Now that Pied Piper's funded,
I have enough money to
move back into my condo.
Oh. Congratulations.
I thought you sold it.
No, I've been AirBNB'ing it out
to cover the mortgage.
But it'll be good to get home.
I've been missing my tub a lot,
and Noah's been using a lot of
hate speech with me lately,
so moving will be a good thing.
All right, guys, think
I'm gonna take off
unless you need me to stick
around, help you transition.
- I...
- By doing what?
I could introduce you to some
of the people that work here.
I made some major inroads with Hiroki.
- No.
- Why would we want that?
Fair... yeah, fair point.
So, welcome to your new home.
Enjoy it, guys. I gave you this.
♪ ♪
Oh.
Sorry. Sorry.
♪ ♪
How was everyone's morning?
- Uh, yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
Let me tell you about mine.
I started my day, as I always do,
by typing my own name into Hooli-Search.
I enjoy the ritual, which
is designed to center me.
But lately, it's been
doing the opposite.
Whose work station is this?
Observe.
(keyboard clicks)
These are all remnants of a time
before I wrote Nucleus down.
Why are we allowing our own technology
to dredge up our painful past?
Why is it that when I type my own name
into my own company search engine,
the fucking Internet rains
shit-bolts down on me?
I want this to stop!
These articles are part
of the public record.
Your point?
Are you suggesting that we alter
the fundamental neutrality of
the Hooli-Search algorithm?
That's a clear violation
of the public trust.
Yelp is threatening to sue
Google for this very thing.
I can't, in good conscience,
order Hooli-Search engineers to do that.
I never suggested anything of the sort.
No Hooli-Search engineer
will ever be asked to alter the
neutrality of the algorithm.
♪ ♪
Patrice: And so, Gavin
doesn't want to see
any more negative mentions
of Nucleus on Hooli-Search.
So... we're gonna alter
the search algorithm?
Of course not. That would be unethical.
What are we supposed to do?
Promote other websites to
outrank the bad Nucleus news?
Do you have any idea how
big a fucking job that is?
Don't you swear at me.
We don't work here anymore.
For 10 more days you do!
Unless you'd all like to quit
and walk away from your
entire severance packages!
Amazing.
(whistling)
Whoa, whoa! Oh.
- Jared. Whoa.
- (laughs)
What's up?
Hi. Umm...
I'm sorry, I'm a little confused.
You... you were supposed
to be out on Tuesday.
Oh, I was, but plans have changed.
See...
I can't really afford
to move or pay rent,
so I'm gonna have to
stay a little while.
Okay, look...
I appreciate your situation,
but... you're breaking the
terms of our contract.
Listen, I don't want to be a dick,
it's just I can't afford
to live around here.
'cause the rent is so high,
because of the tech companies, right?
And you bought this place
with the money you made
working at the tech companies,
so... it kind of all evens out, right?
That... that makes no sense.
I know. Right?
Okay, look, I can give you a few days,
two weeks tops,
but if you're not out by then,
I'm gonna have to take legal action.
This bums me out, man.
I thought you were like
the one cool tech guy.
Me?
Are you sure?
Not anymore.
- ♪ ♪
- Well...
Well, the occupant of a
residence in California
has almost unlimited rights.
I have to get his permission
to enter my property.
I can't turn off the power or the gas,
and I have to hire a lawyer
to start a legal eviction.
That won't be cheap.
Jeez, man. I'm sorry. That sucks.
So, where did you sleep last night?
I did not. How was your sleep?
It was... it was good, yeah.
I mean, I slept like a stone.
It's odd not having to do
everything ourselves, isn't it?
Yeah, I'm... I'm kinda loving it.
Hey, you ready to go to work?
Chef Amy asked us what
we wanted for breakfast,
and I said, "Surprise us."
Could be anything. Let's go!
When was the last time you saw those two
- go anywhere before noon?
- Indeed.
Well, let's go get some
gluten-free waffles.
Oh. Sorry about the surprise.
- I don't care.
- I asked Chef Amy to tell me.
I have too many dietary restrictions
to leave breakfast to chance.
- Makes sense.
- Ah, two of my incubees
off to eat the world.
Be well, work hard,
and know one another.
(chuckles)
Okay.
I recently helped them install
a new CEO at Pied Piper.
I needed to take a more
hands-off approach,
focus on the future...
incubees, like yourself,
with great ideas, like
cataloging malware.
Sexy. Uh, would you care
for another coconut water?
They are the most expensive
unpasteurized variety,
if that's any concern.
Actually, my concern is the room.
It's kind of a dump.
Oh, sure, now.
But with a new coat of paint,
you'll hardly recognize the place
when you move in next month.
Actually...
shit's pivoted.
I need a place next week.
Next week? Oh, shit has pivoted.
Well, I'll talk to the current tenant.
Let him know that the time has... come.
Mother... fuck.
Yeah, put him on a slow
boat to China, so to speak.
I'm sorry. It just slipped out.
I'll ask Chef Amy to
make you something else.
- No, no, no, I want waffles.
- (people murmuring)
I just wanted them to
be a surprise, Jared.
I wanted surprise waffles.
Gilfoyle: Who are these people?
Uh, I don't know.
Did Jack hire engineers already?
These people are not in the
engineering gene pool.
That's right, fellas.
These are our new sales people.
They're the best in the business.
Sales? Uh, Jack?
Jack?
Shouldn't we hire engineers
to build the platform
before we get people to sell it?
No.
God, no!
The system, Richard.
Sales and engineering
are the two pillars
of the Conjoined Triangles of Success.
Yeah.
Engineering and sales must work together
to decide what to build.
Who knows better what the customers need
than the people who actually deal
with the customers every single day?
We're all gonna meet at 1:00, Richard.
You're gonna love these guys.
They're the best.
♪ ♪
So, while the Hooli lawsuit
did hamper our ability to get funding,
it did not slow down the engineering.
Yes, question?
Yeah, Keith, Northeast Regional.
So, you don't foresee any
technical debt issues
slowing our ability to scale?
Actually, no, none whatsoever.
We've identified all
our underlying issues,
and we have a plan in
place for rapid growth.
Uh, yes?
Don, Global Accounts and
Systems Integration.
What kind of growth are
you projecting here?
Well, this may sound a
little bit grandiose,
but it's not unrealistic
to think that we have the potential
for worldwide penetration
on the scale of, say,
Google or Facebook.
This is really great, Richard.
Just keep going.
Sure. Yeah.
Well, in regards to the launch,
we are hoping to go wide,
get it into the hands of as
many people as possible.
Jan, Director, Inside Sales.
- They call me "Jan the Man."
- Oh.
When you say "people," you
mean "companies," right?
- Yeah, we're business-facing.
- Okay, just wanted to clarify.
Actually, no. No, sorry, Jan the Man.
By "people," I do mean "people."
Humans. Consumers.
Uh, Keith, Northeast Regional, again.
Jack told us
we would be selling
directly to businesses.
- He did?
- Doug. I'm shadowing Keith.
- Yes, he did.
- Definitely. I was there.
Don, again.
Well, I'm sorry for
the misunderstanding,
because the plan has always been...
entirely based on the
freemium model, like Dropbox?
You know, you give the platform
away free to consumers,
and then once you have a
big enough user base,
then you sell premium
services to businesses.
If we're giving it away now
and waiting until later to sell it,
what are we doing here now?
I don't know. I don't know.
We could maybe ask Jack...
when he gets back from wherever...
Sorry, one second. Just...
just one moment.
Jack. Sorry, Jack.
Sorry. Excuse me, Jack.
Are you leaving?
Oh, I have this charity wine thing.
Sorry, I committed to it months ago,
but you are killing
it in there, Richard.
Uh, well, actually no.
Sorry. They just said
that you told them that we
would be business-facing?
Ah, they filled you in. That's good.
I was under the impression that
we would be consumer first.
My guys are pretty set on that.
Richard, I read your deck,
and you projected it'll be four
years until we get to revenue?
Uh, yeah.
You know we're in a
bubble right now, right?
Or maybe you don't know. You weren't
around for the last bubble.
You were probably in diapers.
- I was 11.
- Well, I wasn't in diapers.
I don't... I wasn't either.
I was there.
And in March of 2000, do you know
when a four-year plan ended?
April of 2000.
We gotta move, now.
We can't put all of our eggs
in the pot-of-gold-at-the-end-
of-the-rainbow basket.
So, the... the pot of
gold is in the basket?
Richard, these are the best
salespeople in the world,
and when they tell me that
business-facing is the play,
I gotta listen to that, okay?
- That's fair, but it's...
- I'm just asking you
to talk to your guys
about modifying your
platform for enterprise.
I mean, just... just see
how it feels, okay?
And no matter what happens,
I promise you this:
I will never compromise the product.
Okay. Okay.
Fine, I will talk to my guys,
but they're not gonna be happy about it.
No, of course not. They're engineers.
I'll see you later.
I realize this is a Japanese
tradition and that you are Chinese.
I'm not racist.
Yes, Japanese people racist.
- They are horrible.
- No. No, no.
Jian-Yang, in every relationship,
there are ebbs and flows.
- Ebbs?
- Yes.
And although we have flowed,
our relationship now
has come to a permanent ebbing.
- Flow.
- No.
No.
We have come to a permanent ebb.
Do you understand?
So, you want me to leave the house?
Yes. Yes. Very much so.
And so, I thank you...
for our today.
Now you bow.
Bow.
All the way to the waist.
N-no.
- Okay.
- Thank you, Elrich.
Goodbye, little one.
I'm gonna miss you.
Can't say it wasn't fun, Jian-Yang...
you little Cantonese bastard.
(garbage disposal grinding)
- Hey, you like this?
- What are you doing?
Hi, my name's Erlich Bachman.
I'm a lying fuck!
Who... who are you yelling at?
We're the only two people
in the fucking house!
Erlich a liar!
You're not gonna get me to
change my opinion about myself.
Liar! Take that outta there!
I don't know, Richard. I don't
think it's that big a deal.
Really, you don't? You're okay
with being business first?
Granted, it's not what we would
do if we were in charge,
but Jack seems to know what he's doing.
This is fucking amazing.
I feel like I'm in "Minority Report."
And in reality, you're just a minority.
Richard, relax. We're still
building the neural net.
We still get to do all
the cool stuff, right?
Yeah, of course.
We're not scrapping any
peer-to-peer delivery?
No, no, definitely not.
So, we're still doing the same
stuff, just in a different order.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Well, the eviction process
is officially underway,
but my attorney says it
may take up to a year.
- Where are you gonna stay?
- Well, I always have my trick.
All right, I'll bite. What's your trick?
I simply imagine that my skeleton is me,
and my body is my house,
and that way, I'm always home.
Okay. Well...
we are now business-facing.
I don't know if you heard.
That means we have to
rewrite our entire deck.
I just hope it doesn't put
us way the fuck behind.
Behind who? EndFrame sucks
and Nucleus shit the bed, remember?
Yeah, yeah. You're right, you're right.
(chimes)
Wow.
♪ ♪
(sighs) This is endless.
If we worked this hard on
Nucleus in the first place,
we probably wouldn't be
scrubbing it right now.
- Dude, are you done?
- Yup.
How'd you script digest all
those strings so fast?
I don't know. It's just
a predictive loop.
Actually, it's sort of
like a context tree.
♪ ♪
Holy shit.
What's up?
Hey, Jared, why don't we
knock off for tonight?
Just pick this back up tomorrow morning?
Mmm. Agreed.
I'm going on close to 40
hours without good sleep,
and the edges of things are
starting to get a little dancey.
What?
Erlich, thank you again
for allowing me to occupy
a corner of your cozy garage.
It is my hearth and my home.
- What the fuck?
- (yells)
Jian-Yang, Jesus Christ,
don't sneak up on people like
that, you devious little bastard,
especially if they're
cleaning glassware.
You kick me out, but you let him stay.
He's not even an incubee.
No, he's not, and he's not
staying in the house.
He's in the garage, like a
sad bag of potting soil.
Have some compassion.
I mean, the guy rented his place
to some fuckhead tenant who won't leave.
Jared is fucked, Jian-Yang.
He can go to the police.
It's useless. California
law gives landlords
literally no recourse.
So, he can go to court.
Of course, he's going to go to court,
you four-eyed turd.
But in America, the legal
system doesn't work very well,
so it will take at least a year
for the proceedings to even begin.
Do you understand that?
Yes. I stay here for one year.
I pay no rent.
You have no recourse.
That's not always the case. I mean,
sometimes court systems can move faster,
- especially if you have money for...
- I'm going to smoke in my room.
- Oh. Mother fuck.
- Special occasion.
If we stack that same loop on
top of the bit-level encoder
that we took from Hendricks,
and then we tethered it to the
routine we were trying to use...
That would be a huge jump in speed.
This is mega. This is what Hendricks
did at Tech Crunch Disrupt.
I think we just cracked middle-out.
We should probably tell Gavin, right?
Why? He fired us.
You know how much we could get paid
if we took this somewhere else?
♪ ♪
- (phone cameras clicking)
- Fuck off.
Okay, let me get this straight.
First you talked me into
going business-facing,
and now you want to eliminate the
entire neural net from the platform?
Jan, Director, Inside Sales.
They call me "Jan the Man."
Yes, we know, "Jan the Man."
Listen, we have to do neural
net for deep learning.
Look, once we get enough data
flowing through the system,
it will be able to recognize
long-range patterns
and actually learn.
It will be able to optimize
our algorithm on its own,
increasing our already
superior speed and efficiency.
Right? Pretty cool, huh?
But it won't be able to
do that if we delete it.
- Do you get that?
- But you just said it.
It requires a central
repository of data, right?
Businesses want to protect their data.
They're huge pussies when
it comes to security.
Okay, well, we're not cutting
machine learning. We're not.
If we cut that, we might as
well cut peer-to-peer delivery,
and all the efficiencies of the cloud.
Are those still in?
No, those have to go also.
- What?
- Keith, by the way.
I know your name, okay? I
know everybody's name.
Look... (chuckles)
we can't cut everything
about this platform
that makes it revolutionary
just because that's
a little harder for you
guys to sell, all right?
If we want to sell out, let's
just sell all the way out.
Let's just take the algorithm,
jam it into a metal fucking box,
stick it in the back of a
data center somewhere,
so it can't connect to anything,
and it just sits there and no
one even knows it's there.
Doug, still shadowing Keith.
When you say "metal box," you're talking
about a rack-mounted
server-type appliance?
No, no, no. I am using it
as a rhetorical example
of a bad idea.
That's fucking stupid.
Oh my God.
I just need to find Jack. One second.
- Where's Jack?
- He had to go meet his vet.
His vet? In the middle of the day?
Okay, well, what's the vet's address?
♪ ♪
Jack, excuse me. Do you
mind telling me...
Holy shit. What is that?
- Oh, mother of God.
- Richard, what are you doing here?
What do you mean? It's 2:30.
What are you doing here?
My number one breeding
mare went into heat.
Sorry, she's not much for schedules.
Oh God.
Thoroughbreds, Richard.
Natural cover only.
Now, you don't see that
very often, do you?
Nope. Uh...
I had a meeting...
I had a meeting with the sales guys
and Jan the Man...
(stammers)
You know what? Can we talk over here?
This is just hard for me.
(horse grunting)
Look, Jack, you and I have a problem.
Okay, your salespeople are telling me
to cut everything cool
about the platform
just because it's a little
bit harder for them to sell.
But don't you think because they
are such amazing salespeople
that it would be okay for them
to sell the harder stuff?
No. It doesn't work that way.
The way you keep the
best salespeople is,
you need to give 'em
something easy to sell.
(scoffs)
Otherwise, they'd just
go somewhere else.
Okay, well, Pied Piper could
honestly be the global standard
for file compression and storage.
Every mobile device on
the face of the planet
could be able to access their data
as if they had a fiber optic
cable plugged into it.
People in the desert,
people in refugee camps,
people who have nothing could
suddenly have access to everything.
You know, everybody in this industry,
they say they want to make
this world a better place,
but we could actually do it.
We could do it and make
billions of dollars.
- Richard, listen...
- No, you listen to me, Jack.
You promised me that you would
never compromise the product.
So, do you feel like taking some
action and backing me up on this,
because me and my product
feel pretty fucking
compromised right now.
Richard, I don't think you
understand what the product is.
The product isn't the platform,
and the product isn't
your algorithm, either.
And it's not even the software.
Do you know what Pied Piper's
product is, Richard?
Is...
Is it me?
Oh God! No!
No. How could it possibly be you?
You got fired.
Pied Piper's product is its stock.
Its stock?
And whatever makes the
value of that stock go up,
that is what we are going to make.
And maybe sometime in the future,
we could change the world
and perform miracles,
and all of that stuff, and I hope we do.
But, like I told you before,
I'm not going to mortgage
the present for that.
I need to move the needle today.
And now, if you will excuse me.
I paid $150,000
for the semen that's about to
come out of that stallion,
and I would very much like to be
there to see that it happens.
- (cell phone chimes)
- (horse neighing)
Oh! Hey, Richard!
Yes?
I just got a text from
Keith, Northeast Regional.
He says the guys love your idea.
What idea?
- ♪
♪
- Announcer: It's a big world,
but thanks to modern technology,
it's smaller than ever.
Today, business moves
at the speed of light.
You can access your company's
data anywhere, anytime.
But if you can get your data,
who else can get it?
Spies, thieves, criminals,
and foreigners.
What if there was a way
to take all of your company's data
and back it up in a protected enclosure
completely isolated from
the world at large?
Oh no.
The ultimate enterprise
data storage solution.
Now that's what I'm talking about.
This is the game we're playing, team,
so let's win it!
You guys, check it out.
Chef Amy hollowed out a watermelon
and filled it with watermelon jello!
Look, that's actual rind.
- The fuck is that?
- Is that a VCR?
Why does it say "Pied Piper" on it?
Why is everybody so happy?
(reggae music playing)
♪ Everyday ♪
♪ Things are getting worse ♪
♪ Time so hard ♪
♪ Dog and all a look work ♪
♪ Everyday ♪
♪ Things are getting worse ♪
♪ I took him down to the market place ♪
♪ And them laugh at my dog ♪
♪ You never see ♪
♪ Smoke without fire, oh! ♪
♪ You gotta hold your head up higher ♪
♪ Everyday ♪
♪ Things are getting worse ♪
♪ Time so... ♪